Nitin Savant

Software Engineer | Minneapolis, MN nitinsavant@gmail.com | nitinsavant.com

PROFILE

Software Engineer with 5+ years experience in software implementation, systems administration, and project management. I have multiple years of experience building web applications and enjoy tackling challenging problems such as designing efficient data structures for distributed systems.

EXPERIENCE

Conclave, Co-Creator / Software Engineer

Oct 2017 - Dec 2017

- Co-created a real-time, collaborative text editor from scratch in JavaScript
- Built a custom conflict-free replicated data type (CRDT) to resolve conflicts between users; handles 100k operations in less than 1 sec
- Created a peer-to-peer architecture using WebRTC
- Scaled P2P architecture to support dozens of concurrent users
- Presented at Node, Ruby, and JavaScript meetups in Minneapolis

Foodiker, Technical Co-Founder

Mar 2016 - Sep 2016

- Developed company focused on food sustainability
- Designed and developed Rails website at foodiker.com

Laserfiche, Solutions Engineer / Program Manager

2010-2015

- Implemented document management solutions across higher education, government, and financial sectors
- Configured and troubleshooted Windows Server, SQL Server, and IIS environments
- Promoted to manage program of 30+ concurrent projects staffed among 15 engineers, specifically resolving escalated issues related to resources, budget, timeline, and client satisfaction
- Designed tools resulting in elimination of program assistant role, including web-based project status report and staffing tool that enabled the prediction of project start dates

EDUCATION

Arizona State University, M.S. in Electrical Engineering, 2010 **Harvey Mudd College,** B.S. in Engineering, 2008

• Men's Basketball — 2004-2008

SKILLS

JavaScript, Node.js, Ruby, Rails, SQL, Git